Well, I look, I um
didn't trade up and we drafted an LSU
player, so there shouldn't be any
questions.
Yeah.
>> Did you expect before we started to walk
away with four guys?
>> Um, I don't know that we expected four,
but look, we wanted to, you know, we
wanted to add in that area. We wanted to
add speed to our team, which we did. I
think uh you know one thing I think we
we drafted a heck of a relay team
if we want to go that route. Um so look
I think there was a little something for
everyone offense, defense, and special
teams and and you know I think that's a
good thing for us.
>> Yeah, big uh people mover. Um
yeah, just
right there you know he's he's going to
come in and and immediately add size and
power to our offensive line. We'll see
how he develops. Um,
you know, one thing that caught my eye
in this last day was and really the
whole thing is how emotional and
passionate a lot of these guys were. I
know you guys could feel that on on
those Zoom calls afterwards. And we
certainly felt it on the uh on the calls
when you know we talked to the guys to
tell them that they were going to become
Saints and that was really cool.
>> Um I would say that the seven
probably went about what we expected not
necessarily to whom we expected. Yeah.
So there was a little bit of a um
you know shuffle there just not not
amongst the names just about who got who
ended up with him.
>> Yeah I never made I never made one call
to move up from
which will surprise you all. I know it
was reported by a couple of uh people,
but that was completely untrue.
>> Yeah. Yeah, we did we did try to move up
a little bit
on the second day. Yes.
unsuccessfully as noted.
>> Yes.
>> Was there just no interest in moving up?
>> Yeah. I didn't feel like uh felt like
the cost was going to be too high
and we were going to end up with a
really quality player. We we just liked,
you know, a lot of guys in that first
group and and we're going to be
We ended up and really happy with who we
ended up with.
What is it that makes that as simple as
looking at medical record?
How much?
>> Yeah, I think it all comes into play.
All of it. All of it is, you know, all
of it comes into play. I think I think
often times you're looking for Do any of
these injuries, are they causing
problems right now? Are they symptomatic
right now? They keep, you know, are they
the kinds of things that are going to
keep somebody from practicing every day?
You know, is it is it a situation where
if it's a knee, does it swell up every
day and you have to have a lot of rest
days? Um, what's the what's the
likelihood of recurring injury? you
know,
one of the realities of football is that
there's a lot of injuries in our game
and guys, you know, how resilient are
they? So, there's a lot of variables.
>> Yeah,
>> yeah, that is a factor. I I think that
and and I would say this as These guys
are young guys for the most part, right?
They're they're,
you know, 21, 22, 23 years old. Um, and
they're just learning that, you know,
some of the things that they're doing
off the field can impact
um, you know, their availability and and
uh, you know, a lot of guys don't learn
that till they get to the league. And I
think we're pretty sophisticated as a
league. our strength and conditioning
and our performance coaches are pretty
sophisticated in terms of of preventing
injuries and and doing things that that
can help you stay on the field. And so
we'll help him in that regard. And
obviously it's important to him and that
and that's one of the things that you're
looking for. You're looking for guys
that that want to be on the field all
the time. You don't want to miss
practice.
It bothers them
to be in the training room. So
yeah, they're all variables.
No, I wouldn't say it's
and look, we tried in a couple of cases
um
but weren't able to do it. It's just the
circumstances
um
just weren't there for us to make a move
that
that somebody else was going to agree
to.
Yeah, look, I I think look, we liked him
as a player coming out. Um,
you know, I think more than anything,
Brandon has a vision for him fitting
into our defense. Um, and it adds to,
you know, a group that we that we like
already. So, anious to get him here
and obviously he was a high pick
for the Raiders and I'm anious to get
him. a lot coming out like a
professional.
>> Yeah, I I think I think we've got a
couple of different ideas how to use him
and uh you know, we'll see what in this
off season and training camp
that comes to fruition.
>> No, I don't I don't think so.
>> Yeah. Um,
yeah, I think he's he's going to be a
free agent after this.
I I don't I know exactly. I gota
remember what the date final date was,
but
it's a one year trial. See how it goes.
Yeah, I I don't know. I wouldn't say a
plan necessarily, but we have been
talking
about quite some time. So, it didn't
just come up today.
>> No, I I think that um
probably somewhere in between, right?
You always want to add speed to your
team. Um,
and look with us, you know, Rasheed last
year and he was he was that's a big
element of his game and so we wanted to
add that wanted to add some return
ability. Um, we got that. So,
it was
it was conscious
Well, I think you're always, you know,
one of the considerations when you get
later in the draft is obviously the
position and but hey, what's the path to
the roster? And often times for guys,
you know, on this day, the path to the
roster is special teams. So,
it's either they have experience in
their college career or they have the
traits that we are necessary to become
effective special teams players. So
that's definitely part of the
consideration of who we drafted later.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I I mean that's a question for for
Kell really. Um, look, we've added, you
know, a downfield element. We've added
some size. Um,
but we'll see. We'll see how it goes.
>> Yeah, I think again we just, you know,
we're adding talent to the room. We're
adding a developmental 63,
you know, 44 player that that uh, you
know, played at, he didn't play at a
power four conference. He played, you
know, he played for North Dakota State.
So, there's probably some development
that we need to do there.
Jordan Tyson obviously you know he's got
a complimentary skill set to Chris
guys that we have
some of the other guys we have so it's a
good mix right now just talking about it
>> yeah again you know big
we're gonna look pretty good coming off
the bus I think Um
but big powerful you know young man and
uh adds to a great room. So we're
excited to get
you early in the
Taylor
that obviously opens up on defense. Did
you feel good about what you already had
in house that spot and that's why you
didn't or did you
>> No, I I think we probably wasn't in a
perfect world. We went into the draft
thinking, you know, we wanted to get uh
a guy in the early part of the draft at
that position. Um it just didn't work
out.
>> I I think you know a developmental
player. Yeah, for sure.
You know, Brandon refers to these guys
as DBs more than corners, nichles, or
safeties. And so I'm gonna take that t
and just We added some DBs, some of
which are a little more developmental,
and we got to wait till we get into
training camp to see how they fit with
the defense that Brandon wants to play.
>> Yeah, we we've talked about that, you
know, as we get
you know, as we get some of these
undrafted free agents signed and we take
a step back, we're probably have to
adjust some numbers in some different
areas. And yeah, we're a little heavy in
that in that group relative to the
roster right now.
>> Who did?
>> Oh, yeah.
train is that the same timeline that
you're
>> Yeah, I think I think probably I don't
know that we expect him to be ready at
the beginning of training camp, but uh
certainly during the course of training
camp, we're really well aware of of his
timeline
pretty good about it.
>> Yeah. Um yes, because look, we went up
to the pro day. We had him for our local
proday. Um, we enjoyed our visits with
him and he did a good job in their
proday, too. And he was enthusiastic
when we called him. It was fun to It was
fun to feel that excitement from him.
Yeah, I just remember his comment. We
were talking to him about about his
speed
during the local pro day afterwards. And
one of the comments He's never lost a
race.
>> Yeah,
>> there's nothing about about the rest of
the guys that
there's some really good options for us.
Um, but we just felt like, you know,
given where we're at and the talent
level, this was this was for us.
Really excited to get him. I would say
that
pre-draft. Um, when you, you know,
consider where other guys are likely to
go, um, felt really good about Jordan
being
able to us.
Yeah.
>> Was that ever like a I guess do you see
it as a risk?
>> I I think when you look at all these
players, there's there's some risk,
right?
And we all have a vision. We're
projecting them as to what they can be
in our league. And so there's with every
day. And some of it is um more scheme
fit. Some of it may be um you know just
the physical attributes and with him
there was you know he's missed some
games. Um but we you know pretty deep
into that uh into that history at the
end of it.
say the one thing about that set him
apart from
>> there?
>> Yeah, I mean I think there's a lot of
things.
Fast, twitchy, tough, you know, he
he stops well, you know, he he's got a
lot of great skills. Um, a lot of his
catches are first downs and touchdowns.
He makes tough catches. So, It's just
the whole package really. And and look,
if you're going to be top 10 pick in our
league, you better have the whole
package. That's for every position.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
Absolutely. And you feel it when you
talk.
>> And the two paid free agents that you
signed were on offense coming out of the
season. Was that we've got to invest in
this offense. Like, has this been a
mission since January?
>> Yeah. I I think when, you know, when you
go through that postseason evaluation
and you start looking at, okay, here's
here's the holes that we need to fill.
Here's where we need to significantly
get better. There was just more on
offense as it turned out. So,
some it's offense and some it's defense.
So,
offense
>> a little bit. Yeah. You know, size is
good in the NFL, right?
>> Yeah. I Well, I don't know that
I don't know that I would say it like
Tyler's influence. Every quarterback,
you know, you know, wants and needs
weapons, right? They need guys uh to get
the ball to and hopefully they can do
something special with it. And so I
don't think it's unique to Tyler, but I
do think that we need to get that area.
>> Yeah, I think I think for uh yes, we'll
you know reassess the roster in the next
coming weeks.
You know what always happens with this
is that you know teams add players and
you know there's other guys that may
become available through trade. So we'll
take a look at that along with free
agents.
Yeah, I think you know our guys would
say and we would all say that he's got
all the traits, you know, necessary to
to be really productive in the past game
and he's
really willing and able blocker and so
we felt like
giving us some help
would be important and he was very
resilient.
That's a tough program. coaches do a
great job and really tough um
players and he was really resilient and
saved the whole time and was a really
good player for them and they were
really complimentary about about him. So
we were surprised that he was available
to us
when we took him and I wouldn't say that
we went into the draft thinking
but at some point the value just jumps
out
I don't I wouldn't say nervous, but you
know that that's the area every year
that tight end seem to get
fourth round.
So it wasn't a surprise.
Um,
I don't know that I would say it that
way. It's just that I would say that
the strength of this draft wasn't in
good, right?
Didn't seem like there was many as it
normally is. So,
that became a little bit more of a
premium. But, you know, we like
like
we'll see what happens here in the next
few weeks.
I don't know.
>> Um, yeah, I would say he probably is.
Smart kid. Really smart kid. I don't
think he's going to have any problems.
>> Yeah.
>> Um,
yeah. I mean, we talked about that a
little a little bit. Just a feel for
him. He's a great kid. He's a really
really good player. I was really I think
we were all really surprised.
that he didn't didn't get taken a lot
earlier. I don't know the reason behind
it. Um
and really excited when he got when he
got there. It's a great family and he's
going to be successful
100% confident and also you know excited
for him as to where he went. He probably
went to about the best place to
a little bit. Yeah, a little bit. Yeah.
Look, I think I think often times, you
know, you're looking
there's high expectations for these guys
that come draft, right? High
expectations.
And if they don't necessarily meet that
expectation, but they're still good
players, um, you know, they can have a
second chance and have a really good,
you know, career and maybe reach reach a
higher level of success. So hopefully
that's what happens here.
>> You feel good about what you got done?
>> Yes. But I always feel good about it.
I'm half full, right? So yes, I'm feel
It was a perfect No, it didn't come out
perfect in terms of what we might have
laid out prior to the draft, but it was
really good. And it never comes out
perfect. So, yeah, we're excited. We're
excited to get these guys in here.
Excited to get them in for that first
rookie mini camp and then get going.
you still look at all
>> um it's a good question and I would say
that it's a combination of the two.
We've got to fill out the roster, right?
We've got to have a certain number at
every position. Pay attention to that.
But if for example, and this is just
hypothetical, it's not
if for example we were safety, but we
had a really high highly graded safety
out there available to us. We'd go one
over in that area and go short someplace
else because of the grade. So, it's a
combination of the two.
>> Yeah. I mean, we're going to end up with
um 10 maybe
a fewer number than most years.
>> Yeah, I I think that um that was part of
the the trade obviously and
You know, that's a value proposition.
They had a certain value they wanted for
Tyrie and we wanted to pay a certain
value and it just worked out that we end
up back with that pick where we traded
down and uh
and uh so you get that pick and then all
of a sudden man here's a player that we
were considering at the bottom of the
fifth round in the sixth round and man
he's still there so it was kind of like
a no-brain pick for us. um you know play
played at Iowa, played at a high level.
It's a really good program. He's well
coached and it's a guy we can fill it in
at a couple positions because he's we
think he's a pretty versatile athlete
and we might have sw
I I think look, we'd be doing him a
disservice to try to play him at
multiples positions right now. So, we're
going to start.